<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entrepreneurship Development on M1sty</title>
    <link>https://www.m1sty.com/tags/entrepreneurship-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entrepreneurship Development on M1sty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.m1sty.com/tags/entrepreneurship-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 8：Game Simulation Review</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_8_game-simulation-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_8_game-simulation-review/</guid>
      <description>Game Simulation Review Curriculum Structure  Guide to analysis framework for Final Board Presentations on 25 April 2021 Summary of lessons learned in: Integration of value chain, product design, marketing, production, sales, competition  Class 8 PPT Simulation Game Learning Goals You have actually run a business  Selected brand portfolio Distributed products to end users Placed advertisements in the media Decided on employee compensation Scheduled production Worried about profits Managed cash flows  You Have Sweated the Details  Customers were demanding Competitors were unrelenting Investors were challenging Many functional, tactical decisions to master Decisions had to be well-coordinated and timed Cash was always a constraint Constant skillful adjustment was required to stay on course and get ahead  Were You Driven?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 7：Funding your startup</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_7_funding-your-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_7_funding-your-startup/</guid>
      <description>Funding your startup Curriculum Structure  Funding your startup  Venture Capital YCombinator, Seed Capital, Angel Investors, Accelerators and AI Design Studios Kickstarter and other crowdfunding options   Summary  Class 7 PPT New Venture Funding Lean Startup Methodology Forming a Team w. Complementary Skills Steve Blank’s Lessons Learned:
 Schedule a Mixer a month before the start. Interview teams only. Finding product/market fit often requires complementary skills  Hacker/Hardware Hustler Designer Visionary   Encourage inter-departmental/disciplinary teams—business + engineering + science  Steve Blank &amp;amp; the Lean Launchpad Class 3 yrs from Lean Startup to Acquisition</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 6：Deep Learning and Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_6_deep-learning-and-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_6_deep-learning-and-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning and Neural Networks Curriculum Structure  Read Chapter 7 and 8  Review of using scorecards for decision-making - Figure 1 and 2 Why use decision trees? What are neural networks and what are the benefits and risks of deep learning?   Amazon and the Alexa Voice Smart Speaker Breakthrough  Deep Learning and Image and Voice Recognition Breakthroughs Fastest Consumer Adoption in US History Internet of Things and the Connected Smart City   Summary  Class 6 PPT Deep Learning: Image &amp;amp; Voice Applied AI: Perform tasks with AI or apply AI to specific industry verticals  Virtual Assistance Generating Insights Automation of Manual Processes Unlocking Unstructured Data  AI “core” capabilities in Language &amp;amp; Vision NLP Natural Language Processing    https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 5：Blue Ocean Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_5_midterm-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_5_midterm-review/</guid>
      <description>Blue Ocean Strategy Curriculum Structure  Industry Evolution from Emerging to Growth to Mature and Highly Competitive Blue Ocean Strategy: From Technology Innovation to Value Innovation Cirque du Soleil and YellowTail Wines Value Innovation cases Technology and Value Innovation in the Commuter Bicycle Industry  Class 5 PPT Industry Life Cycle &amp;amp; Porter&amp;rsquo;s Five Forces Stafes of the Industry Life Cycle Porter’s Five Forces Analysis of Industry Profitability Industry Life Cycle and Five Forces  Industries in the stages of Maturity and Decline will often seek government intervention or subsidies to help protect the declining industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 4：Machine Learning, InsurTech and Ethical Considerations</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_4_machine-learning-insurtech-and-ethical-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_4_machine-learning-insurtech-and-ethical-considerations/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning, InsurTech and Ethical Considerations Curriculum Structure   How does Machine Learning work and why does data matter? Read Chapter 4 - 7
 Predicting heart attacks with a scorecard and common sense How much data do you need for Figure 2? What is the likelihood of Susan getting a heart attack in the next five years?    AI-enabled insurance: Improving the customer experience, better predictions and reduced claim fraud</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 3：Competitive Advantage</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_3_competitive-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_3_competitive-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Competitive Advantage and Profitability Analysis Curriculum Structure   What is Competitive Advantage and how do you gain and sustain above-average profitability?
 Industry analysis vs firm-level analysis Calculating profit margins in low-cost, differentiated and dual advantage strategies Value chain analysis and profitability analysis Summary    How does this apply to the 3D Printed Carbon Fiber Bike Industry in the Venture Simulation Game?
 Trek and the Traditional Bike Producers Dragon and the Online Bike Startups Pricing, production and sales costs, market share and competitive advantage Summary    Class 3 PPT Competitive Advantage Defined Startegy Toolbox  Firm-level Analysis Industry-level Analysis  Competitive Advantage Analysis Value Chain Analysis    Level of Analysis: One Company vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2：Applied AI in Business</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_2_applied-ai-in-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_2_applied-ai-in-business/</guid>
      <description>Applied AI in Business Curriculum Structure   Reading
 What is Machine Learning and the 5 components of AI systems（Read Chapter 1-3 of AI book）    Material
 Why use Machine Learning for Credit Scoring and deciding to give Loans? What are the 5 components of AI systems What are the 5 components of DoNotPay? Several FinTech Use Cases Summary Questions for reflection    Class 2 PPT Intro to Applied AI Four Pillars of Applied AI  Virtual Assistance Generating Insights Automation of Manual Processes Unlocking Unstructured Data  DoNotPay: Four Pillars of Applied AI?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1：Intro Entrepreneurship Development</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_1_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_1_intro/</guid>
      <description>Topic Topics covered
 The Business Model Canvas Customer Discovery Value Propositions &amp;amp; Minimal Viable Products Channels and Influencers Pivots Revenues and Pricing Models Resources, Activities and Partners Costs, Metrics, Financials and Fundraising Crowdfunding, Venture Capital Hong Kong incubators and accelerators Applied AI in Business The Applied AI Data Business Model Canvas The AI Startup Playbook  MVP Minimum Viable Product
Business Model Canvas Steve Blank Lean Startup Videos Value Proposition Videos</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Textbook：Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning for Business</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_0_textbook_artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_0_textbook_artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-for-business/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning for Business 1.Introduction Topics in the book  What machine learning and artificial intelligence are. The sort o things organizations use artificial intelligence for. What a predictive model looks like. The relationship between artificial intelligence, machine learning and Big Data. The people and tools needed to apply artificial intelligence. How to use artificial intelligence to improve business processes and the bottom line. The legal and ethical issues that need to be considered when developing artificial intelligence based solutions that are going to be used to make decisions about people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web 2.0：A Strategy Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2020/business_book_web-2.0-a-strategy-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2020/business_book_web-2.0-a-strategy-guide/</guid>
      <description>Web 2.0: A Strategy Guide Chapter 1 Users Create Value Flickr and Collective User Value   What is Web2.0
Web 2.0 turbocharges network effects because online users are no longer limited by how many things they can find, see, or down- load off the Web, but rather by how many things they can do, interact, combine, remix, upload, change, and customize for them- selves. This online DIY self-expression benefits businesses and other users, not just individual uploaders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Application in Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2020/business_essay_data-application-in-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2020/business_essay_data-application-in-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>截取自HKU课程E-commerce technologies，Case Study，本人撰写部分
Data Applications: Enterprise This chapter will analyze the application of data commercialization in enterprises from the perspectives of large enterprises as well as small/medium-sized enterprises. There are two development trends in the future: vertical integration of industry and enterprise boundary broadening.
Before we get into this section, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the flywheel effect. The essence of the flywheel effect is to produce motion properties. Once a huge flywheel wants to turn, it needs a vast source of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>精益数据分析</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2020/business_book_jingyishujufenxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2020/business_book_jingyishujufenxi/</guid>
      <description>精益数据分析 先导概念 客户开发法 客户开发方法聚焦于持续地收集用户反馈，这些反馈会对产品和业务的每个阶段产生实质性的影响。
精益创业   客户开发+敏捷软件开发方法+精益生产实践
  “构建-衡量-学习”循环：想法=》构建=》产品=》衡量=》数据=》学习=》想法
  第一部分 精益创业和基本分析技术 精益创业   Airbnb：专人接待式最小可行化产品
 在精益创业理论中，最小可行化产品指足以向市场传达你所主张的价值的最小化产品。但定义中并未对产品的真实程度做出要求。例如，如果你正在考虑创建一种拼车服务，则可以试着用人工牵线搭桥这种原始方式将司机和乘客联系在一起。    数据指标   什么是好的数据指标？
 比较性 简单易懂 比率    什么是正确的数据指标？
 定性指标与量化指标 虚荣指标与可付诸行动的指标（规避虚荣指标） 探索性指标与报告性指标 先见性指标与后见性指标 相关性指标与因果性指标（相关性很好，因果性更佳）    市场细分、同期群分析、A/B测试和多变量分析
  同期群分析
  同期群分析使你能够观察处于生命周期不同阶段客户的行为模式，而非个体的自然生命周期，对所有客户一刀切
  同期群分析适用于营收、客户流失率、口碑的病毒式传播、客户支持成本等数据指标
       精益数据分析周期  精益画布 第二部分 精益分析如何用于创业公司 数据分析框架   精益创业画布模块及相关指标</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
