<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entrepreneurship Development on M1sty</title>
    <link>https://www.m1sty.com/tags/entrepreneurship-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entrepreneurship Development on M1sty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.m1sty.com/tags/entrepreneurship-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Applied AI in Business</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/ed_2_applied-ai-in-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/ed_2_applied-ai-in-business/</guid>
      <description>Applied AI in Business Curriculum Structure   Reading
 What is Machine Learning and the 5 components of AI systems（Read Chapter 1-3 of AI book）    Material
 Why use Machine Learning for Credit Scoring and deciding to give Loans? What are the 5 components of AI systems What are the 5 components of DoNotPay? Several FinTech Use Cases Summary Questions for reflection    Class 2 PPT Intro to Applied AI Four Pillars of Applied AI  Virtual Assistance Generating Insights Automation of Manual Processes Unlocking Unstructured Data  DoNotPay: Four Pillars of Applied AI?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro Entrepreneurship Development</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/ed_1_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/ed_1_intro/</guid>
      <description>Topic Topics covered
 The Business Model Canvas Customer Discovery Value Propositions &amp;amp; Minimal Viable Products Channels and Influencers Pivots Revenues and Pricing Models Resources, Activities and Partners Costs, Metrics, Financials and Fundraising Crowdfunding, Venture Capital Hong Kong incubators and accelerators Applied AI in Business The Applied AI Data Business Model Canvas The AI Startup Playbook  MVP Minimum Viable Product
Business Model Canvas Steve Blank Lean Startup Videos Value Proposition Videos</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
