<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HKU on M1sty</title>
    <link>https://www.m1sty.com/tags/hku/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HKU on M1sty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.m1sty.com/tags/hku/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 4：Top-k Queries</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_top-k_1_content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_top-k_1_content/</guid>
      <description>Top-k Queries Background Multidimensional Data  Flat relational tables Multimedia feature vectors Data warehouse data Spatial data Text documents  Attribute Types  Attributes of multidimensional tuples may have variable types  Ordinal (e.g., age, salary) Nominal categorical values (e.g., color, religion) Binary (e.g., gender, owns_property)   Basic queries: range, NN, similarity  Basic Queries  (Range) selection query  Returns the records that qualify a (multidimensional) range predicate Example:  Return the employees of age between 45 and 50 and salary above $100,000     Distance (similarity) query  Returns the records that are within a distance from a reference record.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 4：Top-k Query Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_top-k_2_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_top-k_2_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>TA &amp;amp; NRA Qustion A website posts information about apartments. Suppose that there are 10 apartments to be sold, together with their ratings($a_1$) and prices($a_2$), as listed in the table below. The website employs an aggregation function f = 0.6*$a_1$+ 0.4*$a_2$ to rank these apartments.
Q1) Write down two lists of apartments, in descending order of $a_1$ and $a_2$.
Q2) Use the TA algorithm to find the two best apartments in terms of f.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment：Clusterings</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_clusterings_3_assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_clusterings_3_assignment/</guid>
      <description>Clusterings Theoretical exercises on K-means Qustion 1 Answer 1 Input Points and Set Centroids Input P1=(0,0), P2=(0,1/2), P3=(1,1/2), P4=(1,1), P5=(4,0), P6=(4,1), P7=(5,1)
Set P1=(0,0) and P4=(1,1) as centroids
Reclustering  STEP 1  For each point P2, P3, P5, P6, P7, determine the closest centroid
   d(a,P1) distance d(a,P4) distance     d(P2,P1) $\sqrt{ 0^2 + (\frac{1}{2})^2 }$ d(p2,p4) $\sqrt{ (\frac{1}{2})^2 + 1^2 }$   d(P3,P1) $\sqrt{ (\frac{1}{2})^2 + 1^2 }$ d(P3,P4) $\sqrt{ 0^2 + (\frac{1}{2})^2 }$   d(P5,P1) $\sqrt{ 0^2 + 4^2 }$ d(P5,P4) $\sqrt{ 1^2 + 3^2 }$   d(P6,P1) $\sqrt{ 1^2 + 4^2 }$ d(P6,P4) $\sqrt{ 0^2 + 3^2 }$   d(P7,P1) $\sqrt{ 1^2 + 5^2 }$ d(P7,P4) $\sqrt{ 0^2 + 4^2 }$    P2 is assigned to the red cluster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise：Clusterings</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_clusterings_2_exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_clusterings_2_exercise/</guid>
      <description>Clusterings K-Means Algorithm Input Points Centroids Reclustering step 1 Recomputing centroids step 2 Recomputing the centroids step 3 Final Clustering K-Means++: Main Intuition Probaility distribution Sampling points Examples K-means- To understand why K-means++ use some randomness we compare it against the following algorithm which we call it K-means–:
The algorithm selects the first point randomly. Let t be any step of the algorithm, with 2 ≤ t &amp;lt; k. Let C be the set of points chosen at step t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic：Clusterings</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_clusterings_1_content/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_clusterings_1_content/</guid>
      <description>Clusterings Background What is Cluster Analysis  Finding groups of objects such that the objects in a group will be similar (or related) to one another and different from (or unrelated to) the objects in other groups  Intra-cluster distances are minimized Inter-cluster distances are maximized   Notion of a Cluster can be Ambiguous  Applications of Cluster Analysis  Understanding  Group related documents for browsing, group genes and proteins that hav similar functionality, or group stocks with similar price fluctuations   Summarization  Reduce size of large data sets    What is not Cluster Analysis  Superviesd classification  Have class label information   Simple segmentation  Dividing students into different registration groups alpgabetically, by last name   Results of a query  Groupings are a result of an external specification   Graph partitioning  Some mutual relevance and synergy, but areas are not identical    Types of Clusterings Introduction   A clustering is a set of clusters</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
