<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spatial Networks on M1sty</title>
    <link>https://www.m1sty.com/tags/spatial-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spatial Networks on M1sty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.m1sty.com/tags/spatial-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Networks：Content</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_spatial-networks_1_content/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_spatial-networks_1_content/</guid>
      <description>Spatial Networks Background Network Distance  In many real applications accessibility of objects is restricted by a spatial network  Examples  Driver looking for nearest gas station Mobile user looking for nearest restaurant     Shortest path distance used instead of Euclidean distance SP(a,b) = path between a and b with the minimum accumulated length  Challenges  Euclidean distance is no longer relevant  R-tree may not be useful, when search is based on shortest path distance   Graph cannot be flattened to a one-dimensional space  Special storage and indexing techniques for graphs are required   Graph properties may vary  directed vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Networks：Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_spatial-networks_2_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_spatial-networks_2_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s algorithm review A* search algorithm review Nearest neighbor search exercise Question Consider a spatial network database, which includes a road network graph G and a set of points of interest P. The points in P can only be located on the vertices or edges of G. Each point of interest is with some labels (at least one), e.g., &amp;lsquo;school&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;hotel&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;restaurant&amp;rsquo;. The points P are indexed by an R-tree RP based on location and by an inverted file (see the demo below) IP based on the labels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
