<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on M1sty</title>
    <link>https://www.m1sty.com/tags/content/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on M1sty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.m1sty.com/tags/content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 4：Top-k Queries</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_top-k_1_content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/atdm_top-k_1_content/</guid>
      <description>Top-k Queries Background Multidimensional Data  Flat relational tables Multimedia feature vectors Data warehouse data Spatial data Text documents  Attribute Types  Attributes of multidimensional tuples may have variable types  Ordinal (e.g., age, salary) Nominal categorical values (e.g., color, religion) Binary (e.g., gender, owns_property)   Basic queries: range, NN, similarity  Basic Queries  (Range) selection query  Returns the records that qualify a (multidimensional) range predicate Example:  Return the employees of age between 45 and 50 and salary above $100,000     Distance (similarity) query  Returns the records that are within a distance from a reference record.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic：Clusterings</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_clusterings_1_content/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_clusterings_1_content/</guid>
      <description>Clusterings Background What is Cluster Analysis  Finding groups of objects such that the objects in a group will be similar (or related) to one another and different from (or unrelated to) the objects in other groups  Intra-cluster distances are minimized Inter-cluster distances are maximized   Notion of a Cluster can be Ambiguous  Applications of Cluster Analysis  Understanding  Group related documents for browsing, group genes and proteins that hav similar functionality, or group stocks with similar price fluctuations   Summarization  Reduce size of large data sets    What is not Cluster Analysis  Superviesd classification  Have class label information   Simple segmentation  Dividing students into different registration groups alpgabetically, by last name   Results of a query  Groupings are a result of an external specification   Graph partitioning  Some mutual relevance and synergy, but areas are not identical    Types of Clusterings Introduction   A clustering is a set of clusters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic：Association(2)</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_association_1_content2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_association_1_content2/</guid>
      <description>Improvements to A-Priori PCY Algorithm Introdution  Main observation: during pass 1 of A-priori, most memory is idle. Use that memory to keep additional info to improve storage during pass 2 of A-priori. Passes &amp;gt; 2 are the same as in A-Priori.  Pass 1  Use a hash function which &amp;ldquo;bucketizes&amp;rdquo; item pairs, that is, maps them to integers in $[1,k]$. Each &amp;ldquo;bucket&amp;rdquo; i in $[1,k]$ is associated with a counter $c_i$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic：Association(1)</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_association_1_content1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/dm_association_1_content1/</guid>
      <description>Frequent Itemsets and Association Rules Market Baskets The Market-Basket Model   A large set of items, e.g., things sold in a supermarket.
  A large set of baskets, each of which is a small set of the items, e.g., the things one customer buys on one day.
  A general many-many mapping (association) between two kinds of things.
  The technology focuses on common events, not rare events (“long tail”).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
