<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entrepreneurship development and FinTech ventures in Asia on M1sty</title>
    <link>https://www.m1sty.com/categories/entrepreneurship-development-and-fintech-ventures-in-asia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entrepreneurship development and FinTech ventures in Asia on M1sty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.m1sty.com/categories/entrepreneurship-development-and-fintech-ventures-in-asia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 8：Game Simulation Review</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_8_game-simulation-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_8_game-simulation-review/</guid>
      <description>Game Simulation Review Curriculum Structure  Guide to analysis framework for Final Board Presentations on 25 April 2021 Summary of lessons learned in: Integration of value chain, product design, marketing, production, sales, competition  Class 8 PPT Simulation Game Learning Goals You have actually run a business  Selected brand portfolio Distributed products to end users Placed advertisements in the media Decided on employee compensation Scheduled production Worried about profits Managed cash flows  You Have Sweated the Details  Customers were demanding Competitors were unrelenting Investors were challenging Many functional, tactical decisions to master Decisions had to be well-coordinated and timed Cash was always a constraint Constant skillful adjustment was required to stay on course and get ahead  Were You Driven?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 7：Funding your startup</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_7_funding-your-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_7_funding-your-startup/</guid>
      <description>Funding your startup Curriculum Structure  Funding your startup  Venture Capital YCombinator, Seed Capital, Angel Investors, Accelerators and AI Design Studios Kickstarter and other crowdfunding options   Summary  Class 7 PPT New Venture Funding Lean Startup Methodology Forming a Team w. Complementary Skills Steve Blank’s Lessons Learned:
 Schedule a Mixer a month before the start. Interview teams only. Finding product/market fit often requires complementary skills  Hacker/Hardware Hustler Designer Visionary   Encourage inter-departmental/disciplinary teams—business + engineering + science  Steve Blank &amp;amp; the Lean Launchpad Class 3 yrs from Lean Startup to Acquisition</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 6：Deep Learning and Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_6_deep-learning-and-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_6_deep-learning-and-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning and Neural Networks Curriculum Structure  Read Chapter 7 and 8  Review of using scorecards for decision-making - Figure 1 and 2 Why use decision trees? What are neural networks and what are the benefits and risks of deep learning?   Amazon and the Alexa Voice Smart Speaker Breakthrough  Deep Learning and Image and Voice Recognition Breakthroughs Fastest Consumer Adoption in US History Internet of Things and the Connected Smart City   Summary  Class 6 PPT Deep Learning: Image &amp;amp; Voice Applied AI: Perform tasks with AI or apply AI to specific industry verticals  Virtual Assistance Generating Insights Automation of Manual Processes Unlocking Unstructured Data  AI “core” capabilities in Language &amp;amp; Vision NLP Natural Language Processing    https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 5：Blue Ocean Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_5_midterm-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_5_midterm-review/</guid>
      <description>Blue Ocean Strategy Curriculum Structure  Industry Evolution from Emerging to Growth to Mature and Highly Competitive Blue Ocean Strategy: From Technology Innovation to Value Innovation Cirque du Soleil and YellowTail Wines Value Innovation cases Technology and Value Innovation in the Commuter Bicycle Industry  Class 5 PPT Industry Life Cycle &amp;amp; Porter&amp;rsquo;s Five Forces Stafes of the Industry Life Cycle Porter’s Five Forces Analysis of Industry Profitability Industry Life Cycle and Five Forces  Industries in the stages of Maturity and Decline will often seek government intervention or subsidies to help protect the declining industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 4：Machine Learning, InsurTech and Ethical Considerations</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_4_machine-learning-insurtech-and-ethical-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_4_machine-learning-insurtech-and-ethical-considerations/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning, InsurTech and Ethical Considerations Curriculum Structure   How does Machine Learning work and why does data matter? Read Chapter 4 - 7
 Predicting heart attacks with a scorecard and common sense How much data do you need for Figure 2? What is the likelihood of Susan getting a heart attack in the next five years?    AI-enabled insurance: Improving the customer experience, better predictions and reduced claim fraud</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 3：Competitive Advantage</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_3_competitive-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_3_competitive-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Competitive Advantage and Profitability Analysis Curriculum Structure   What is Competitive Advantage and how do you gain and sustain above-average profitability?
 Industry analysis vs firm-level analysis Calculating profit margins in low-cost, differentiated and dual advantage strategies Value chain analysis and profitability analysis Summary    How does this apply to the 3D Printed Carbon Fiber Bike Industry in the Venture Simulation Game?
 Trek and the Traditional Bike Producers Dragon and the Online Bike Startups Pricing, production and sales costs, market share and competitive advantage Summary    Class 3 PPT Competitive Advantage Defined Startegy Toolbox  Firm-level Analysis Industry-level Analysis  Competitive Advantage Analysis Value Chain Analysis    Level of Analysis: One Company vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2：Applied AI in Business</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_2_applied-ai-in-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_2_applied-ai-in-business/</guid>
      <description>Applied AI in Business Curriculum Structure   Reading
 What is Machine Learning and the 5 components of AI systems（Read Chapter 1-3 of AI book）    Material
 Why use Machine Learning for Credit Scoring and deciding to give Loans? What are the 5 components of AI systems What are the 5 components of DoNotPay? Several FinTech Use Cases Summary Questions for reflection    Class 2 PPT Intro to Applied AI Four Pillars of Applied AI  Virtual Assistance Generating Insights Automation of Manual Processes Unlocking Unstructured Data  DoNotPay: Four Pillars of Applied AI?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1：Intro Entrepreneurship Development</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_1_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_1_intro/</guid>
      <description>Topic Topics covered
 The Business Model Canvas Customer Discovery Value Propositions &amp;amp; Minimal Viable Products Channels and Influencers Pivots Revenues and Pricing Models Resources, Activities and Partners Costs, Metrics, Financials and Fundraising Crowdfunding, Venture Capital Hong Kong incubators and accelerators Applied AI in Business The Applied AI Data Business Model Canvas The AI Startup Playbook  MVP Minimum Viable Product
Business Model Canvas Steve Blank Lean Startup Videos Value Proposition Videos</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Textbook：Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning for Business</title>
      <link>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_0_textbook_artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.m1sty.com/2021/edafv_0_textbook_artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-for-business/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning for Business 1.Introduction Topics in the book  What machine learning and artificial intelligence are. The sort o things organizations use artificial intelligence for. What a predictive model looks like. The relationship between artificial intelligence, machine learning and Big Data. The people and tools needed to apply artificial intelligence. How to use artificial intelligence to improve business processes and the bottom line. The legal and ethical issues that need to be considered when developing artificial intelligence based solutions that are going to be used to make decisions about people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
